

MAIK COSTA

Java Software Engineer

- 🛛 Av. Odair Santanelli,300 Guarulhos/SP
- ☑ maikcosta@gmail.com
- **\&** +55 11 982.129.613

SOCIAL

- in @maikcosta
- @maikcosta
- @ @maikcosta

PROFILE

Extensive experience with legacy systems, integrations and new implementations. Focused on his studies in Java, JavaScript and Python languages, which can be consulted on the GitHub platform. Experience in requirements gathering, deployment, systems support, information integrity and CI / CD. MBA Information System Projects and degrees in two technological areas Development of Web Systems and Computer Networks, currently working as Software Engineers at SoftExpert, applying good practices acquired through certifications (DevOps, Agile Scrum and Lean It) applying engineering frameworks of software with the use of object-oriented standards, with priority on improving the process and efficiency in the construction of solutions, maintenance of software and execution of operational processes.

EXPERIENCE

Java Software Engineer

From 05/2021 to today | SoftExpert

Participation of Team Back-End System Engineers, focusing on the following SoftExpert Suite resources;

- General search
- · Email engine
- Dynamic entities
- My Tasks
- · Data sources
- Data set
- API Gateway

ERP TOTVS Protheus Specialist

From 05/2021 to 11/2021 | Azul Seguros

Porto Seguro "Bllu" product

- Participation in the agile product team
- Squad member with technical bias TOTVS Protheus
- Support in the integration of the FRONT-END and BACK-END fronts between legacy systems
- Testing and Approval of new features
- Support support in production cases

Scrum Master

From 03/2021 to 04/2021 | Access System and Process

Responsibilities:

- Disseminate and help the team in adopting agile practices;
- Support the Product Owner and team members to create backlog items. clear and concise form;
- Conduct and facilitate the ceremonies: Daily, Planning, Review and Retrospective;
- Evaluate with the team the progress of deliveries in Sprints and Kanban;
- Participation in the Retrospective ceremony, evaluating with the team the

evolution of deliveries;

- Support the development team, removing the daily impediments and helping in understanding the business;
- Acting in Squads with different products, such as: TOTVS Protheus, Front-End and Apps.
- Leverage team characteristics, such as proactivity, good communication and good relationship in multidisciplinary teams
- Promote self-organization
- Conflict management

Tools: Jira Software and Monday

EDUCATION

MBA Information Systems Projects

University Descomplica

2020 - 2021

Systems and Telecommunications Networks Technology

University Eniac

2006 - 2008

Web Development Technology

University Cruzeiro do Sul

2004 - 2006

SKILLS

- Html
- Angular
- Java
- JPA
- Phyton
- SpringBoot
- JavaScript
- JSF

LANGUAGES

Portuguese

• English

INTERESTS









Games

Movies

Football

Music

IT Supervisor

From 2008 - 2021 | Santo Angelo

Information Technology Management involving the area of ERP (TOTVS) and infrastructure systems. Responsible for area indicators (CAPEX and OPEX, projects and technological evolution) Participation in the revitalization project of the company's ERP system. Involvement in all project areas such as requirements gathering, user interviews, documentation, schedule definition and monitoring, physical x financial evolution, resource control, internal and external and all other project needs. Together with other managers, we redefined processes and implemented new features. Maintenance and Development customizations, application of packages, database management, environment configuration, maintenance in data dictionary, update of releases in TOTVS Protheus systems, versions 8,10, 11 and 12, knowing the modules: Billing, Financial, Inventory, Purchasing, Management Accounting, Tax Books, Document Control, Entrance Inspection, Non-Conformity Control, Production Control Planning, Metrology, Personnel Management, Electronic

Point and TAF. Service demand management with ITSM tools.

CERTIFICATIONS

DevOps Lead

Certification Number: **5F60DCC**☑

Agile Scrum Fundamentals

Certification Number: **5F60DCD**☑

DevOps Essentials

Certification Number: **5F60DC7**[™]

Lean IT Essentials

Certification Number: **5F60DC8**☑

Scrum Essentials

Certification Number: **5F60DC9**☑

Scrum Master Foundation

Certification Number: **5F60DCA**□

Scrum Product Owner Foundation

Certification Number: **5F60DCB**

REFERENCES

Tech Lead Manager

Cintia Trissila Arthur Schimidli

cintia.rensch@softexpert.com arthur.schmidlin@softexpert.com